Guide to the Neal Van Devender Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Neal Van Devender papers
1964-2003
1964-1966
SC0893
Van Devender, Neal.
1.5 Linear feet
The bulk of the collection consists of syllabi, notes, homework reports, and exams from math, engineering and aeronautics classes at Stanford, 1965-66. Other materials include letters received pertaining to employment offers, 1966; two letters from Alvy Ray Smith, 1966 and 1985; photographs taken at Stanford, including some of Alvy Ray Smith, 1965-66; and other miscellaneous materials pertaining to his time at Stanford.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Neal Van Devender earned his master’s degree in aeronautics and astronautics at Stanford University in 1966.
Description of the Collection
The bulk of the collection consists of syllabi, notes, homework reports, and exams from math, engineering and aeronautics classes at Stanford, 1965-66. Other materials include letters received pertaining to employment offers, 1966; two letters from Alvy Ray Smith, 1966 and 1985; photographs taken at Stanford, including some of Alvy Ray Smith, 1965-66; and other miscellaneous materials pertaining to his time at Stanford.
Access Terms
Smith, Alvy Ray.; Van Devender, Neal.; Aeronautics--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - A.A. 210a (Compressible Flow) 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A.A. 210b, notes, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A.A. 210b, syllabus, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A.A. 210b, homework and exams, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A.A. 210c, syllabus, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A.A. 210c, notes, homework and exams, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - A.A. 220 (Aero. Phys. Meas.), syllabus, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - A.A. 220, notes, exams, experiment reports, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - A.A. 231 (Experimentation in Aeronautics and Astronautics), syllabus, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - A.A. 231, notes, final exam, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - A.A. 231, experiment reports, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - A.A. 240a (Structural Analysis) 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - A.A. 240b, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - A.A. 242a (Classical Dynamics) notes, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - A.A. 242a, homework and exams, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - A.A. 280c (Rocket Technology), notes, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - A.A. 280c, homework #4, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - A.A. 280c, homework and exams, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - A.A. 290 (280) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - E.M. 242 (Hydro and Aerodynamics), notes, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - E.M. 242, homework and exams, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - E.M. 243 (Hydro and Aerodynamics), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Math 106 (Complex Variables), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Math 131 (Partial Differential Equations), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Math 132 (Partial Differential Equations), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - PSSC Physic Study Guide – optics and mechanics, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - PSSC Physic Study Guide – E&M and modern physics, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Aeronautics and Astronautics [SU] Newsletter Fall 2003 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Biographical clippings (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Boeing application 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Commencement 1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Graduate School of Business application [SU] 1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Letters received 1965-68 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, Stanford (including some of Alvy Ray Smith), 1965-66 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Smith, Alvy Ray, letters, 1966, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Stanford University correspondence and forms, 1964-66 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Employment Applications and Resume, 1965-1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)